Guide to the Spargel Production Rosie the Riveter Media Collection OH.081
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spargel Production Rosie the Riveter Media Collection
2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spargel Productions (Firm)
OH.081
1.8 Linear Feet in two manuscript boxes and one record carton
70 DVDs
This collection consists of interviews of women who entered the industrial workforce (automobiles, shipbuilding, aircraft manufacturing, electrical equipment manufacturing, and transportation) during the years of World War II (1939-1945). Interviews we were created on digital video for use in the Spargel Productions new media project "The Girl With The Rivet Gun." Topics covered include gender relations and discrimination at work, union experience, industrial work, family roles, transitioning from rural to urban environments, race relations, and post-war employment experiences. Transcripts are available for all interviews.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Rosie the Riveter film project was conducted in conjunction with Spargel Productions, LLC and the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives beginning in 2010. The accession number associated with this collection is 2010.014.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of thirty-three interviews with women who entered the industrial workforce (automobiles, shipbuilding, aircraft manufacturing, electrical equipment manufacturing, and transportation) during the years of World War II (1939-1945). Topics covered include gender relations and discrimination at work, union experience, industrial work, family roles, transitioning from rural to urban environments, education, race relations, and post-war employment experiences. Transcripts are available for all interviews.
Historical
These interviews were recorded as a part of a collaborative media project by Spargel Productions and New York University's Tamiment Library. These oral histories were created on digital video and portions of them are used in the Spargel Production new media project "The Girl With The Rivet Gun." They are being preserved at the Tamiment Library.
Working class women -- History.; World War, 1939-1945.; Gender discrimination.; Gender identity -- United States; Race relations -- United States.; Equality -- Economic aspects -- United States.; Consumerism.; Sexual Orientation; Automobile industry workers; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States -- Personal narratives.; African American women -- Economic conditions; Sex discrimination against women.; Women -- Employment -- United States.; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Women labor union members -- United States.; Oral histories (literary works); Rural conditions.
- Jerre Kalbas, February 17, 2010
  - Access Copies (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-000, OH-81-001)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-001)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-001)
  - Preservation Copy (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-000)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43257
- Esther Horne, February 19, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-002)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-002)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-002)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43258
- Violet Johnson, April 14, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-003)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-003)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-003)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43259
- Idilia Johnston, April 14, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-004)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-004)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-004)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43260
- The Baltimore Rosies, April 16, 2010
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-05A - OH-81-05B)
  - Access Copies (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-05A, OH-81-05B)
  - Transcripts (Box 3, Folder OH-81-005)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43261
- Susan Taylor King, April 16, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-006)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-006)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-006)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43262
- Bonnie Gifford, May 6, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-007)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-007)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-007)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43263
- The Robey Girls, May 7, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-008)
  - Transcripts (Box 3, Folder OH-81-008-01, OH-81-008-02)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-008)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43264
- Lucetia Jane Tucker, June 28, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-09)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-009)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-09)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43265
- Signe Nakashima, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-10)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-010)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-10)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43266
- Mary Anne Diamond, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-11)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-011)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-11)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43267
- Mildred Sargent, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-12)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-012)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-12)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43268
- Evelyn Davidson, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-13)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-013)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-13)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43269
- The Carters, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-015)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-013)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-015)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43270
- Mazie Mullins, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-016)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-016)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-016)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43271
- Dorice Hamilton, June 27, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-014)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-014)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-014)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43272
- Idamae Mason, June 28, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-017)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-017)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-017)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43273
- The Powells, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-018)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-018)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-018)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43274
- Edith Lyons, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-022)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-022)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-022)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43275
- The Mathauser Twins, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-019)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-020)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-019)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43276
- Arkie Huffman, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-020)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-019)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-020)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43277
- Shirley Clark, June 28, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-021)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-021)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-021)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43278
- Frances Ellis, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-023)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-023)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-023)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43279
- Arlene Crary, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-024)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-024)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-024)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43280
- Catherine Gaultier, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-025)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-025)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-025)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43281
- Eileen Tench, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-026)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-026)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-026)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43282
- Mabel Myrick, June 25, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-027)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-027)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-027)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43283
- Nell Young, June 25, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-028)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-028)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-028)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43284
- Winona Gillespie, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-029)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-029)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-029)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43285
- Thelma Edgar, June 26, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-030)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-030)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-030)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43286
- Marion Yagoda, July 12, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-033)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-031)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-031)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43287
- Angeline Fleming, July 12, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-032)
  - Transcripts (Box 3, Folder OH-81-032)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-032)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43288
- Eva Chenevert, July 13, 2010
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Dvd OH-81-033)
  - Transcript (Box 3, Folder OH-81-033)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Dvd OH-81-033)
  - Digital Recording, cuid43289